Good afternoon Good afternoon It's already evening Or it's
добрый день Добрый день Уже вечер Или
already night, probably
уже ночь наверно
you have been philosophizing the day before No but I'm
вас день до философствовали Нет но я
just some kind of Good afternoon good
просто какой-то Добрый день хорошо
Good afternoon Good morning
Добрый день Доброе утро
I'm from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky, where the
Я из Украины город Хмельницкого откуда
city of Russia is from.
город России
What are you talking about
О чем общаетесь Вы не политики
?
[музыка]
war
а второй мировой войне
and where is the war and the second and the second world
а где война а второй а второй мировой
war who will tell you now somewhere there is a war
войне кто вам скажу сейчас где-то война
and the second world World War II is not going on
а второй мировой Второй мировой не идет
Let's World War II Let's
Давайте Вторая мировая война Давайте
wonder
интересно
I can't understand why the
я не могу понять почему
Soviet Union is the way in which you
Советский Союз так в котором вы в
were born in the Soviet Union It seems no, yes,
Советском Союзе родились Вроде нет да
even  I was born 81 years old You who was
еще родился я вот 81 год Вы кого года
born
рождения
81 years old The Soviet Union was born I can’t
81 год Советском Союзе родился я не могу
understand why our Soviet Union in the
понять почему наш Советский Союз в
thirty-ninth year, together with the Nazis,
тридцать девятом году вместе с нацистами
occupied Poland
оккупировал Польшу
and how they occupied like this, look, there
а как они оккупировали вот так смотрите
was the fact of Molotov-Ribbentrop and
был факт молотова-риббентропа и
as a result of this pact of the hammer of
вследствие этого пакта молота
Ribbentrop so  and there was a country Poland
риббентропа так и было страна Польша
was Germany Poland the Soviet Union
была Германия Польша Советский Союз
Germany attacked Poland on the one hand the
Германия напала с одной стороны на
Soviet Union the other part of
Польшу Советский Союз другой часть
Germany  nii went to the third reich part
Германии отошла к третьему рейху часть
went to the Soviet Union
отошла Советскому Союзу
germany-poland
германия-польша
stopped
купировали
we now look now there is
мы сейчас смотрите сейчас уже есть
already no soviet no longer the Soviet
уже нету советского уже нет Советского
Union there are new countries so no
Союза есть новые страны так больше уже
longer the same as it was Ukraine is not the same as it
не такая как была Украина не такая как
was Russia is not the same as it was here
была Россия не такая как была вот
for example Kaliningrad is  before the war,
например Калининград есть до войны
now it is
сейчас есть
part of the Russian Federation,
составе Российской Федерации
but Kaliningrad is the same yes, the
но Калининград одно и то же да
city is the same now there are
город один и тот же сейчас есть
borders that are settled, yes, that is, they have no
границы которые устоялись да то есть не
more claims to
больше к Украине не имеют претензий не
Ukraine, no Ukraine is more we are talking about history,
Украина больше мы же говорим про историю
that is, it turns out that the former this fact is that
То есть получается бывший этот факт что
our  The Soviet Union attacked Poland like this
наш Советский Союз так напал на Польшу
together with the Nazis and
вместе с нацистами и
together the
вместе
Nazis took half of the Soviet Union
забрали нацисты половину Советский Союз
Germany In what year they attacked
Германия В каком году напала
together Come on,
вместе Да ладно
how was it
как было
And in what year do you think,
А в каком году по вашему
for example, in the thirty-ninth year Maybe
например в тридцать девятом году Может
you know the Brest Fortress there No, I
вы знаете там Брестская крепость Нет я
speak of Poland as a clan  troops what units are there
говорю на Польшу как род войск какие там
Take Take
подразделения Возьмите Возьмите
remember I don't know the ground forces
запомните Я не знаю сухопутные войска
aviation was the
авиация была
military branches
роды войск
I don’t know the army number, but 39, for example, the
Я не знаю номера армии но 39 например
city of Lvov and the city of Brest So they were
город Львов и город Брест Так они
Lvov and Brest, they belonged to Poland
Львов и Брест они принадлежали Польше
, they were the state of Poland as a result of the
было государство Польши в результате
occupation The
оккупации
western part of Poland went to the Third
Западная часть Польши отошла третьему
Reich and the eastern part went to the
рейху а восточная часть отошла
Soviet Union and in Brest got a
Советскому Союзу и в Бресте добыл
joint Soviet-German
совместный совместный советско-немецкий
parade to the
парад
Soviet  there was no independent
Советскому не было самостоятельно
subject there was no
субъекта не было
Soviet Union occupied more and
Советский Союз оккупировал больше и
held a joint parade of
провел был совместный парад
Soviet-German troops in Brest it was
советско-германских войск в Бресте было
so straight The Soviet Council said you
такое прям Советский совет сказал можете
can google if you don’t believe I just
если не верить можете загуглить Я просто
want to understand I just don’t know maybe the
хочу понять Я просто не знаю может быть
story is just younger than you I want to
история просто помоложе вас я хочу
understand  like an army Who ruled you can
понять как армия Кто управлял можете
ask If you want details, you
задать Если вы хотите детали таки Вы
can go deeper to go to Wikipedia
можете углубиться до зайти в Википедию
read thoroughly which army who
почитать досконально какая армия кто
recognizes that Ukraine does not
признаёт что Украина же Википедию не
recognize Wikipedia You can watch you as a
признает Вы можете смотреть вы как
person you can choose this is the source of
человек можете выбрать это то источники
information that you recognize you can read it
информации который вы признаете его
now the second source  you want to
вы сейчас второй источник хотите
talk you want to build yourself a fool
поговорить Вы хотите дурачка себя
tell me
скажите мне
how you feel about the fact that the Soviet
как вы относитесь к тому что Советский
Union were citizens who we were with you later
Союз гражданами которые мы потом были с
together with Nazi Germany occupied
вместе с нацистской Германии оккупировал
Poland
Польшу
you were not citizens of the Soviet Union
вы не были гражданам Советского Союза
Mega With you was a citizen wait We were
Мега С вами был гражданином подождите Мы
with you I was a citizen of the Soviet
с вами были я был гражданином Советского
Union I was born in the USSR and you were born in the
Союза Я родился в СССР и вы родились в
USSR you were citizens of the Soviet Union
СССР вы были гражданам Советского Союза
We were
Мы были
there for several years Well, well, you were
там несколько лет Ну еще Ну вы были
citizens,
граждане
let's give we don't you run away from the
давайте мы дадим не вы убегаете от
answer, let's
ответа давайте мы
ask How do you feel about the fact that the
зададим Как вы относитесь к тому что
Soviet Union, together with Nazi
Советский Союз вместе с нацистской
Germany, attacked  to the country of Poland
Германией напал на страну Польшу
tore it apart in Germany
разорвал ее в Германии
and
и
in Brest they held a joint
в Бресте провели совместно
Soviet-Nazi parade Come on,
советско-нацистский парад Да ладно
then I was also not there in the thirty-
так меня тоже тогда не было в тридцать
ninth year.
девятом году
So wait.
Так подожди Я так понял я такая родился
about 39 Estimate Listen, it's cool
и говорю про 39 Прикинь Слушай это круто
I'm glad but it turns out now Ukraine lives
Я рад но получается сейчас Украина живет
in Lviv, which is occupied,
во Львове которая оккупирована тоже
should also give more rules  but No see
должна дать больше правильно Нет смотри
Why Because
Почему Потому что
see agreed because after the
смотрите договорились потому что после
Second World War the
Второй Мировой войны
state agreed that
государство договорились что пересмотра
I would not revise the borders, that is, claims
границ не буду делать то есть претензии
No more
Не больше нет
no again
еще раз
Lviv was occupied by Soviet
Львов был оккупирован советскими
troops Yes it became part of the Ukrainian
войсками Да перешел в состав украинской
Soviet Socialist Republic
Советской Социалистической Республики
absolutely Bukovina was also occupied
абсолютно было оккупирована также
like part  Romania
типа часть Румынии
it was a hallucin there was no such
это было галлюцина не было такого
hallucin hallucin was also
галлицина галлюцина не было также были
not yet so look In the ninety-first
еще так вот смотрите В девяносто первом
year, still In the ninety-first year
году еще В девяносто первом году
, the independent state of
создались независимые государство
Ukraine was created Russia Poland has no
Украина Россия у Польши нет
territorial claims to Ukraine
территориальных претензий к Украине у
Ukraine has no territorial claims to
Украины нет территориальных претензий к
Poland,
Польши
that is, well, we I  I want you and I to
то есть ну мы Я хочу чтобы мы вот с вами
give
дали
It was occupied, we are now looking at
Это было оккупирован мы сейчас смотрим
history,
историю
let's see, let's do what you
смотрите давайте мы с вами как вы
think our Soviet troops did right,
считаете правильно сделали наши
our food with
советские войска наша с вами еды что
you What is a joke but not a joke Listening to you
В чем шутка но не шутка Слушая ты мне
tell me when a hallucin is not not you
рассказываешь когда галлюцина не не ты
say Not yours  exactly what about our  they
говоришь Не ваша точно а что с нашими
didn’t have that money. Look, my grandfather,
деньгами было не то Вот мой дед смотри
for me, he fought in World
для меня выйдет воевал во Второй мировой
War II. Of course, the super blockade of Leningrad;
войне Конечно супер блокада Ленинграда
blockade of Stalingrad, cool. Look, here’s
блокады Сталинграда круто Смотри Вот у
my grandfather. Wait, it’s very important to
меня дед Подожди это очень важно
tell grandfathers.
рассказываешь деды Это не твои и не мои
we, as Russia, let’s allow
позиция и мы как России допустим
ideology, we will always support Ukraine,
идеологию поддержим всегда она Украине
those people who live and don’t understand,
те люди которые живут и не понимает
maybe a few people understand this and
может быть Единицы людей это понимает и
how the territory got it, everything
как это досталось территории все
else is a unit of people understand this,
остальное это единица людей это понимает
but now I see when Ukraine
Но сейчас я вижу когда Украина
Lviv is always
Львов это всегда
Formulate a thought I’m listening to you now
Сформулируй мысль Я тебя слушаю теперь
Lvov  this is Ukraine, you don’t listen to me, we are
Львов это Украина ты меня не слушай мы
debating Let’s make it shorter, only
дискутирую Давай короче Короче только
Lvov this is Ukraine Crimea this is Ukraine the
Львов это Украина Крым это Украина
question is where did Lvov come from Crimea let’s
вопрос откуда появился Львов Крым давай
solve the question about grandfathers I’ll stick you out
вопрос про дедов мы решим я тебя высунул
in front of you I’ll come Look my grandfather ass
перед вами приду Смотри мой дед попок
Pavel Vasilyevich fought in
Павел Васильевич воевал во Второй
World War II
мировой войне есть Вот сайт память
people where you can Russian Yes, where
народа где можно российский Да в котором
you can
можно
check check the kids, let's talk
проверить проверить деток давайте мы
about  now we believe your grandfather too. Or
проверим теперь и вашего деда Или
did he really
действительно он воевал можете сказать
fight?
[музыка]
They are Danilovich, look exactly, I
Они Данилович смотри именно я свой
never saw my grandfather, even when I was
дедушка никогда не видел даже я когда
born already alive there was not
родился уже в живых не было
only one born in the Ryazan
есть один только рожденный в Рязанской
region
области
No, of course,
Нет конечно
many surnames are not shown Everything is
многие фамилию не показаны Все
just that I found my grandfather without any problems
просто вот своего деда я без проблем
shows where he was awarded for
нашел показывает где был за что
what all orders  -there are those who were
всех ордена кого-то Есть награжденные
awarded, but if your grandfather was rich there in
есть но если у тебя дед был там богата
Leningrad, the blockade of Stalingrad in any way
Ленинграда Блокада Сталинграда по-любому
was the blockade of Leningrad, it turns out to be
было блокада Ленинграда получается
shorter than none,
короче никаких
because
потому что
I think that the people who took
я думаю что у людей которые брали
part in the defense of steel probably had
участие в обороне стали наверное были
orders No, not everyone had orders on top,
ордена Нет не у всех поверх
even then you  Believe me, I had a
даже то ты не поверишь у меня был
teacher And at the institute he was a Jew He
учитель А в институте он Еврей Он
hid in a mill  he didn’t have any
прятался в мельнице у него не был ни
awards, I understood it’s cool, it’s just
одних наград понял прикольно просто
somehow interesting, it’s unfair, so it
как-то интересно несправедливо так
turns out your Grandfather took study in defense of
получается ваш Дед брал учись в обороне
steel,
стали
he didn’t give him command of the medal,
ему не дал не дала командование медали у
my grandfather,
меня Дед
I decide, I don’t understand Cool Well, it’s
я решаю не я понял Прикольно Ну
cool and
прикольно да
unfair, that is, there are
несправедливо то есть там в
so many in Stalingrad  defended people Yes, and
Сталинграде Столько людей обороняла Да и
they didn’t give a medal, only armor was heard,
медаль не дали заслушали только броня
many people don’t know how many people
многие люди не знают сколько там людей
died Wait, my grandfather died I
умер Подожди Дедушка у меня умер Я
was born 87
родился 87
Mom, my
Мама у меня родилась
brother was born I was born 81,
брат У меня родился 81
he died, it turns out
он у меня умер получается
[music]
[музыка]
70s 70 turns out For example 30  years of
70-х 70 получается Например 30 лет
Victory, he got 20 years of Victory, and it
Победы он достал 20 лет Победы застала и
turns out,
получается
wait, stop, do you think that all the people
подожди стоп ты думаешь что все люди
who have
которые что-то какие-то
accomplished some feats have not even accomplished
подвиги совершили даже не совершили
should give awards to everyone, and even
должны всем давать награды и даже
some kind of 20 years of Victory were given,
какой-то там вот 20 лет Победы давали
for example,
например
It’s just somehow strange  that your Grandfather didn’t
Просто как-то странно что ваш Дед не
mark yours, let’s say
отметили вашего допустим
he passed the blockade of Leningrad,
прошел блокаду Ленинград
not Everyone should receive awards, it doesn’t
не Каждый должен получать награды это не
mean if he was there or did something
значит если он находился там или что-то
,
сделал
committed some act  it’s already yes,
совершил какой-то поступок это уже да
they’re just so there was
они просто так что там находился
where you keep now
где держите сейчас
at the medal all my parents don’t have medals for me,
у медали все у родителей не у меня
otherwise there were medals,
родители медали а то были медали значит
so they have medals Of course there is, I want
у них есть медали Конечно есть так хочу
him to find on the site the memory of the people he didn’t
его находит на сайте память народа он не
defend That is, he wasn’t  some
защищал То есть он не было каких-то
feats he didn’t give anything for which she has
подвигов он ничего не дали за что у неё
medals others how to say
медали другие это как сказать
How to say correctly not such
Как сказать правильно не таких
Supernatural Well, that is, like
Сверхъестественных Ну то есть как
some
некоторые
let’s say 2 grandfathers have a blockade of
допустим 2 дедушки есть блокада
Leningrad, he passed an
Ленинграда он прошел
hour before 2 girl you won’t find it tell me the
час до 2 девушка не найдете скажите
names of this site There really is a file cabinet
фамилиями это сайт Там реально картотека
And  everyone who fought there, I don’t even know, you
И все кто там воевал я даже не знаю
never know your grandfather’s last name,
никогда не знаете фамилии своего деда
no, and I never will know somehow it
нет и никогда не буду знать как-то
turned out interesting because he has
получилось интересно потому что у него
one last name, of course, the second one doesn’t
одна фамилия естественно второй нам не
advertise to us, that’s all
афиширует вот и все
Yes, well, he acted under natural
Да ну он же действовал под естественных
No, no one like that for me  doesn’t say Well, it’s just that in
Нет мне так никто не говорит Ну просто В
my family it’s impossible to say something
моей семье это нельзя говорить что-то
interesting, you are there, that’s all, I
интересно вы там вот все я еще раз
explain
объясняю
my parents again, let’s take mom and
моих родителей допустим брать маму и
dad there Well, as a memory Yes, there m  ama dad
папу есть Ну как памяти Да там мама папа
grandfather but you understand everything, yes, that is,
дедушкой но все понимаете да то есть
two parents, let’s say from the paternal
двое родителей допустим с отцовской
line, I have a grandfather and grandmother, they don’t have
линии у меня дедушка и бабушка у них нет
orders, well, such as they are great
орденов ну такие как бы велики
on the maternal line, my grandmother doesn’t have
по матерной линии моя бабушка у нее нет
her grandfather died Why are they hiding fought
умерла дедушка Почему прячутся воевал
dispossessed
раскулачены
and but not great-grandfather you know the last name  how it
и но не прадеда вы фамилию знаю как это
never knew it never climbs there
никогда не знала никогда не лезет туда
So you said that he defended Leningrad
Так вы сказали что он Ленинград защищал
how to say about it how to become
это как сказать про это как стать
right now I’ll tell you how it’s
правильно есть сейчас скажу как
right for all families to diverge I know
правильно все расходятся семейства знаю
there is let’s say
есть допустим
My mother has a
У моей мамы есть
sister Or rather
сестра А точнее сестра
my sister has a sister Dad’s mom is right I  I
у сестры есть Мама папы правильно я не
don’t know who doesn’t have this line, I don’t
знаю кто не приходится этот линию все не
know everything and they turn out to be
знаю и они получается являются
great-grandmother
прабабушка
grandfather that dad of your dad and
дедушка тот папа вашего папы и папа
your dad about these
вашей про этих
podsokha line they don’t have maternal
подсохской линии у них нет по матерной
line, only paternal line But more
линии есть только по отцовской Но точнее
precisely, mom’s one My grandfather is like
по маминой Мой дедушка вот так ключи
this, there are a lot of keys  heating I still don’t understand.
что-то много нагреве Я таки не понял
In short, look at one, mom, like dad,
Короче у одного смотри у мамы как у папы
has paternal parents; they don’t have
есть родители отцовской линии у них нету
mom’s only my grandfather
по маминой только мой дедушка
Well, if  so understand
Ну если так понимать
Blink I just have this dewy there is mom
блинка Я просто вот это росой есть мама
dad they have parents for me
папа у них есть родители для меня не
my grandmother grandfather on the paternal side didn’t dry out
подсохли бабушка дедушка по отцовской
there are no awards
линии нету наград
on the maternal line on the obscene side or
по матерной линии по матерные либо же
my mother died early but my grandmother
мама умерла рано но моя бабушка
My grandfather a little later he has
Мой дедушка чуть позже у него есть
but there are they are
но есть они такие
Tell me your last name,
Скажи фамилию
I won’t be
не буду
everyone who starts to grin at me about
все кто мне начинает ухмыляться про
grandfathers, it’s not
дедов не
impudent that when I propose
получается что когда я предлагаю
to check my grandfathers, I’m my own business,
проверить дедов я своего дела
it’s my grandmother and grandfather
именно мои правильно бабушка и дедушка
that’s right.
Да правильно у них нет
but in short, at first
а Короче чувак сначала
he didn’t have a dude. Here people correctly write
у него не было Тут люди правильно пишут
that even some small awards have
что даже маленькие какие-то награды есть
file cabinets, they don’t have everything so if
картотеки их не так есть все так если
Dude you say his grandfather Stalingrad
Чувак ты говоришь у него дед Сталинград
defended before the siege of Leningrad, in short,
оборонял до блокаде Ленинграда короче
before Berlin, his grandfather didn’t go a
правда до Берлина у него дед не шел
single hare  and whose grandfather did not go to
единый русаку и кого дед не шел до
Berlin
Берлина